Jaison Binns

Phone: 610.348.4284 | Email: binns.jaison@live.com | Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/jaison-binns/ |

Portfolio: jaisonbinns.github.io/

Summary

Well-rounded web developer, seeking a software engineering position. Two years of experience designing and implementing intuitive user features and applications for multiple clients. Over 5 years of experience using JavaScript and ReactJS.

Skills

Front End

- JavaScript
- ReactJS
- React Redux
- React Router
- Redux Thunk
- Redux DevTools
- VueJS

Front End Design

- Material UI
- Semantic UI
- Bootstrap
- InVision
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Draw.io
- Markdown

Other

- PHP
- NodeJS
- Python
- MongoDB
- MySQL
- Version control (Git)
- Google Cloud Platform

Experience

Self-Employed / Freelance Developer

June 2020 - PRESENT, PHILADELPHIA, PA

• Create websites and optimize SEO for local restaurants.

GoMoto, Inc. / Development & Operations

April 2019 - PRESENT, PHILADELPHIA, PA

- Created front end notification user feature for the client web dashboard.
- Automated operational data entry tasks using Python, BeautifulSoup, Selenium, and Excel.
- Compile, analyze and monitor product performance and data for clients exceeding revenue goals for over 75% of clients.
- Provide on-call hardware support and support support for all clients and the operations team.

Vibespot App, LLC / Business Development

OCTOBER 2018 - APRIL 2019, PHILADELPHIA, PA

- Redesigned the 2.0 UX/UI experience using MS Paint and InVision resulting in 2,000+ app downloads and 10+ venue and collegiate partnerships over 5 months.
- Provided strategic user stories as a Agile team member based on measured, compiled user feedback.
- Conducted and reported software quality control.
- Analyzed user data to develop a new strategic business plan resulting in decreased new user acquisition cost from \$5/user to \$2/user.

Education

Villanova University / Political Science, Computer Science (Double Major)

May 2018, VILLANOVA, PA

Dean's List, St. Thomas of Villanova Scholar, Comcast Leaders/Achievers Scholarship,
Co-launched Big East esports invitational